Alison Altomari

3823 Sunset Drive Los Angeles, CA 90027 (609) 306-1571 Altomari.Alison@gmail.com www.alaalison.com

Merging my rich experience in marketing with my unparalleled passion for food and agriculture, I excel at working directly with producers and purveyors to build successful brands and connecting the dots between consumers and real food.

Professional Experience

California Olive Oil Council

Marketing Director

Berkeley, CA September 2012 - December 2013

- Spearheaded the Council's first media dinners in San Francisco, New York and Baltimore; collaborating with reputable chefs to create menus, educating influential media guests and tastemakers, and generating awareness of the California olive oil industry
- Strengthened the extra virgin certification program by implementing new evaluation methods for the taste panel and oversaw the certification of 450+ oils, training as a professional taster
- Successfully completed redesign of the council's website and logo; transforming the brand image as well as membership communications

Monvinic Restaurant

Stage (Culinary Apprentice)/Sommelier Barcelona, Spain January – April 2012

- Gained an informal education in the Spanish language as well as authentic Catalan cuisine by training under each kitchen station, reporting to the executive chef
- Facilitated the weekly produce orders and selection from 82 local food purveyors, visiting local markets and live seafood auctions

à la Alison, www.alaalison.com

Owner/Creator

Philadelphia, PA Sept. 2010 – Present

- à la Alison started as a food blog; a way to share recipes, educate readers on cooking techniques, food sourcing, and sustainability issues. à la Alison has evolved to connect travel storytelling with seasonal, regional recipes and produce small-batch preserves and pantry items
- Personal recipe published in Food52's Cookbook, Fall 2012
- Selected to host a video segment for the 2011 Atlantic City Food & Wine Festival

Agency 51 Advertising

Account Executive

Philadelphia, PA June 2010 – January 2012

 Consistently achieved quarterly goals and campaign success through measured reach of target audience as well as an increase in clients' customer base and sales

Education

Drexel University

Philadelphia, PA

Graduated magna cum laude, June 2010

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration
Marketing Concentration, Communications Minor

Member of the Drexel Pennoni Honors College

Received the following scholarships and awards for academic excellence: A.J. Drexel, Dean of LeBow, Honors College, Betsy Z. Cohen, and Paul R. Moul Scholarships as well as Dean's Service and Warren Cooper Awards

Member of the Student Advisory Board to the Dean of Drexel's LeBow Business College

Computer Skills

Experienced photographer; trained in photo editing with Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop Elements

Proficient in Microsoft Office, website management, and HTML editing

Activities

Freelance writer and photographer

Certified Yoga Alliance Instructor

Model for Mill Mercantile and RTH shop

- Collaborated with clients to develop and execute integrated creative campaigns for consumer and business-to-business marketing initiatives across print, broadcast, electronic, and collateral media
- Developed creative briefs, production schedules, invoicing, client budget proposals, and internal agency records